{
    "id": "2581fd08ffa1461981e169af85acf1a1",
    "title": "Tenses",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We often ………………….. over the fields in the evening.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "walks",
                "walk",
                "walking"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "According to the time table, the train …………………… at",
            "description": "The simple present is commonly used to talk about time-tabled events. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "is arriving",
                "arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "My dog …………………. everything. He is almost human.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "understood",
                "has understood",
                "understands"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We went out although it …………………….. a bit late.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My feet were sore because my shoes …………………. badly.",
            "description": "Fit and fitted are both possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "fit",
                "fitted",
                "fits"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………. my job because I was ill for six months.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most common tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "lose",
                "had lost",
                "lost"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "During the holidays, I ………………….. a lot of reading.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "have done",
                "was doing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………….. to Paris for the weekend.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about a future event when the arrangement already exists.",
            "answers": [
                "are going",
                "go",
                "have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………. to anyone.",
            "description": "The present perfect is common with never and ever.",
            "answers": [
                "never apologized",
                "has never apologized",
                "have never apologized"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You never ……………………… me finish a sentence.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lets",
                "let",
                "have let"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. cooking or cleaning.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about likes, dislikes etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "don’t enjoy",
                "am not enjoying",
                "doesn't enjoy"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It ……………………… a long time since we met.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to indicate that an action or situation started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}